<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ec2 on AWS HPC Workshops</title>
    <link>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/tags/ec2.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in ec2 on AWS HPC Workshops</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/tags/ec2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>a. Pre-Requisites</title>
      <link>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/02-requirement_notes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/02-requirement_notes.html</guid>
      <description>The following requirements will be necessary to follow this guide.
 A laptop with an internet connection running Microsoft Windows, Mac OS X, or Linux. An Internet browser such as Chrome, Firefox, Safari, Opera or Edge. Familiarity with common Linux commands.  Should you have any question when running this workshop as a group or on your own, do not hesitate to talk to you coordinator or contact us at AWS HPC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a. Login the AWS Console</title>
      <link>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/03-aws-console-login.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/03-aws-console-login.html</guid>
      <description>Depending on conditions in which you are running this guide, you may access the AWS Console through direct sign-in (here) or as directed by your trainer. To log in you will need to enter your AWS Account ID or alias, IAM user name, and Password that as provided to you for this lab.
After you log in, you will see the main AWS Management Console. Take a few minutes to check it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>g. Create an EC2 Instance</title>
      <link>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/08-start-ec2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/08-start-ec2.html</guid>
      <description>Now that you are getting familiar with the AWS Console and AWS CLI we will raise the bar and do the following: create an SSH key-pair on you AWS Cloud9 instance, create an instance then access it.
Generate an SSH Key-pair SSH is commonly used to connect to Amazon EC2 instances. To allow you to connect to your instances we will generate a key-pair using the AWS CLI on your AWS Cloud9 instance as shown below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>h. IAM and Roles</title>
      <link>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/09-ec2-s3-iam.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/09-ec2-s3-iam.html</guid>
      <description>You will encounter an issue now! But that&#39;s normal and we will explain why.
 Access to resources by users and services is controlled by Identity and Access Management (IAM). For example, IAM permissions can be added to a policy then a role which can be attached to a user user, group role (admins, devops) or a service (Amazon EC2 to access Amazon S3, Amazon Lambda to access Amazon SQS).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>