<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>s3 on AWS HPC Workshops</title>
    <link>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/tags/s3.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in s3 on AWS HPC Workshops</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/tags/s3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>e. Start with the AWS CLI</title>
      <link>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/06-start-aws-cli.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/06-start-aws-cli.html</guid>
      <description>Your AWS Cloud9 Environment should be ready. We will now get familiar with it, introduce you the AWS CLI then create an Amazon S3 bucket with the AWS CLI. This bucket will be used at the next stage.
Your AWS Cloud9 IDE The AWS Cloud9 IDE is similar to a traditional IDE you can find on virtually any system. It is composed of a file browser, listing the files located on your instances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>f. Using Amazon S3</title>
      <link>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/07-work-with-s3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/07-work-with-s3.html</guid>
      <description>Now that we have access to the AWS CLI, we will use it to create an S3 bucket then upload a file to this bucket. While those steps could be done using the AWS Console, they will give you a good idea of what can be done with the AWS CLI. In addition if interested, you can find more details about S3 on the related documentation page.
Every bucket must have a unique name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>g. Create an EC2 Instance</title>
      <link>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/08-start-ec2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://master.d2fvrafk9v089j.amplifyapp.com/02-aws-getting-started/08-start-ec2.html</guid>
      <description>Now that you are getting familiar with the AWS Console and AWS CLI we will raise the bar and do the following: create an SSH key-pair on you AWS Cloud9 instance, create an instance then access it.
Generate an SSH Key-pair SSH is commonly used to connect to Amazon EC2 instances. To allow you to connect to your instances we will generate a key-pair using the AWS CLI on your AWS Cloud9 instance as shown below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>